字幕碓矗浩嬗鲭影字幕M
字幕特效：101eagle
褐疲101eagle
上UP：101eagle
露z?
Ruth?
我妻子在哪
Where's my wife?
古特曼先生 你可不能@油低翟诒翅我一跳
Mr. Guttman!You can't be sneaking up on me like that!
我太太呢 露z在哪Y
Where is my wife?Where is Ruth?
很抱歉 古特曼先生
I'm sorry, Mr. Guttman,
你太太大s一周前^世了
your wife passed away about a week ago.
噢
Ah.
抱歉 你是?
I'm sorry. Who are you?
我叫保拉
My name's Paula.
曾是古特曼太太的o理
I was Mrs. Guttman's nursing aide.
你家我再多待一芍
Your family asked me to stay on for another week or two.
去吃c早餐吧
Let's get some breakfast.
吃完早餐你感X好些的
You'll be feeling better after breakfast.
你的鞋在哪
Where are your shoes?
等等 我去o你拿拖鞋
Hold on, let me get you some slippers.Tell you what.
用你的帽子去Qp拖鞋 可以
Trade your hat for some slippers, okay?
好了 M戆
All right. Now come in.
- 早安 煞 - 早安
Good morning, Zev.  Good morning.
但你]有很I 早餐和往常一由俚每z
I hope you're not too hungry.Breakfast is crummy as usual.
]PS 我不是很I
That's okay.I'm not too hungry.
她是塞R 你太太以前的朋友
That's Cele. She was friends with your wife.
我知道她是l 我知道
I know who she is.I know who she is.
能o我私聊的rg
Could you give us a minute, please?
噢 ]}
Oh, no problem...
他是R克斯
Max.
你]必要告V我所有人的名字
You don't have to tell me everyone's name.
今晚是槁督z服实淖钺嵋煌
Tonight is the last night sitting shiva for Ruth, yes?
你不得你f^露z死後
Do you remember what you said you would do
你要做什N
when Ruth died?
不得了
No.
]事 ]事
It's okay. It's okay.
我
I...
下了所有事
wrote everything down
所以你
so you...
起淼
could remember.
跟我 谏U姆先生
Come on, Mr. Rosenbaum.
H鄣
Darling.
你知道@照片什Nr候照的
Do you know when this picture was taken?
他Y婚的r候照的
It's from their wedding day.
1946年
1946.
你是在德遇奶奶的
Did you meet nanny in Germany?
噢 不 不是
Uh, no, no.
我在美遇她的
I met her in America.I met her...
在康尼
Coney...
- 在康尼u -
Coney Island.  Yeah.
嘿 槭颤N不拿o你哥哥看看呢
Why don't you show this to your brother, eh?
快看@
Adam, look at this!
o 把@放口袋Y
Here. Put this away in your pocket.
F在
Now,
站起
stand up.
告V所有人你累了
Tell everyone you're tired,
然後自一人看完
and go read it alone.
自一人
Alone.
你累了
You're tired.
Yeah, yeah.
就@ 好的
Yeah. Good.
原我 我
Forgive me, I...
我有c累 我想我去睡X了
I'm a little tired,I think I should go to bed.
好的 爸爸
Yeah. Okay, Dad.
真是漫L的一周
It's been a long week.
是啊
Yeah.
- 佩恩站  - 是的
Penn Station, right?  Yeah.
最後通知
Last call!
49湖I列要l了
49 Lake Shore Limited!
最後通知
Last call!
最後通知 要_了
Last call,49 Lake Shore Limited!
那是你
Is that your mother?
是的
Yeah.
她不和你一起
She's not coming with you?
不 我去找我爸爸
No. I'm going to see my dad.
噢
Oh.
所以你是一人咯
So, you're traveling all alone?
不是一人 我的兄弟在那呢
I'm not alone.My brothers are right over there.
噢?
Oh?
噢 我看了
Oh, I see.
你也是去克利夫m
Are you going to Cleveland too?
是的
Yeah.
槭颤N不坐wC呢 那痈快
Why don't you fly?It's faster.
我也不知道
I don't know.
@可不是好理由
That's not a good reason.
你@不知天高地厚的小孩
You're a real whipper snapper, aren't you?
那你槭颤N不坐wC去克利夫m呢
Why don't you fly to Cleveland?
三wC票太F了
Three plane tickets is too expensive.
那是我爸f的
That's what my mom and dad said.
好吧 @是好理由
Well, that is a good reason.
我不坐wC是因槲遗笥言谒o我的信Y
I don't fly because my friend told me to take the train
告V我要坐火
in the letter he wrote to me.
我想@也是好理由
I guess that's a good reason, too.
我叫泰勒
My name is Tyler.
很高dJR你 泰勒
Nice to meet you, Tyler.
我叫煞
My name's Zev.
真是奇怪的名字
That's a strange name.
在希伯碚ZY 它的意思是"狼"
In Hebrew, it means "Wolf."
真酷
Cool!
我槟阌了所有事
I have planned everything for you.
你必精实绦羞@些步E
You must follow these steps precisely.
每做完一就掉一
Cross them off as you accomplish each task.
我已通知^警方 他向社^l出了
We've notified the police and they've issued
y色警K臃911系y
a silver alert as well as a reverse 911
我...我@竭M全力
to the community, our...our staff is doing all that we can.
- _y以接受... - 我只是不敢相信
It's upsetting.  I just can't believe
l生的@一切
this is happening.
我感到f分的抱歉
I can't tell you how sorry we all are.
我密切留意每人
We do our best to keep an eye on everybody,
但...我相信你能理解的
but... I'm sure you can understand.
我能偷绞颤N
Is there anything we can do to help?
除了付X你看G人有e的
Besides paying you to lose people?
你父H有信用卡
Does your father have a credit card?
他一旦使用你可以y行M你
You can tell them to call you if he uses it.
著
Listen.
你母H的o工告V我
Your mother's nursing aid told me that
你父H最近特e糊T
your dad's been very confused lately.
是的 他患有V呆
Yeah, yeah.That's because he has dementia.
而@也是起初我母H把父H一起У竭@淼脑因
And that's why my mother brought them here in the first place.
我明白 但是
I understand that. However,
通常在配偶死亡後
it's very common after the death of a spouse
出F更多J知障K
for more signs of neurocognitive disorders to emerge.
你有]有注意到你父H的情w波
Have you noticed that your father's been having mood swings?
而且他缀醪辉琴了
And he rarely plays the piano anymore?
我察X到了一些 查斯
I've noticed a few things, Charles.
我想那r我
I guess we were...
在你母H的事情上太操诹艘灾领段]有理@些
so busy with your mom that I just dismissed them.
安心吧 我他在你知郧捌桨不淼
Let me reassure you,we'll have him back here before you know it.
在@些情r下
In these situations,
人不走太h
people never wander too far.
露z?
Ruth?
?
Adam?
你奶奶在哪
Where is your grandmother?
?
Adam?
你奶奶呢
Where is your grandmother?
你在跟我f 煞
Were you talking to me, Zev?
我你奶奶在哪
I asked you where your grandmother is.
一在~s州 一在俄亥俄州
One is in New York.One is in Ohio.
你妹妹呢
Where is your sister?
我]有妹妹
I don't have a sister.
e玩那玩意毫
Stop playing with that thing.
回答我
Answer me.
你...好 煞
Are... are you okay, Zev?
我在哪
Where are we?
在火上
We're on a train.
去哪
To where?
克利夫m
Cleveland.
克利夫m?
Cleveland?
你要去一朋友
You're going to see a friend.
什N朋友
What friend?
o你了你口袋Y那封信的朋友
The one who wrote you the letter in your pocket.
能把我的[Co我了
Can I have my PSP back?
露z死了
Ruth is dead.
煞
Zev,
我要去和我兄弟坐一
I'm going to sit with my brothers for a little bit.
- 你好 - 嗯?
Excuse me.  Yeah?
嗨 我... 我鹤釉诨疖上r你和他挨著
Hi. Uh...My son there said that you were sitting
而你看起碛行┖T了
next to him on the train and that you seemed a little confused.
噢 是的
Oh, yes, that.
- 我Υ烁械胶鼙歉 - 噢 不不
I'm sorry about that.  Oh, no, no, no.
你不需要道歉 我...
There's no need to apologize. We...
- 只是想_J你]事 - 噢我]事的
just want to make sure you're okay.  Oh, yes, I'm okay.
xx你 我很好
Thank you. I'm okay.
~...你要去哪需要兔
Um... You need help getting somewhere?
不用 有人斫游业
No, no.Someone will be meeting me here.
我朋友f他e一
My friend said that he had a...
有我姓名的牌子
sign with my name on it.
好的 我湍阏
Okay. Well, we'll help you find him.
@些到
The cars are just down here.
你是姓古特曼
Is your last name Guttman?
是的
Yeah.
你坐的看起砗r髦
Looks like you're riding in style.
再 煞
Bye, Zev.
再 再
Goodbye. Goodbye.
走吧 孩子
Let's go, boys.
- 古特曼先生? - 是的
Mr. Guttman?  Yeah.
好的
Good.
- 下午好 - 下午好
Good evening.  Evening.
我怎偷侥隳
How can I help you?
我朋友向我推]了你的店
My friend recommended your shop to me.
好的 D告你的朋友我很感x他的推]
Well, tell your friend we appreciate the recommendation.
- 你想要拿哪N呢 - 噢...
What are you looking to pick up?  Oh...
小一c的
Something small.
然有
Sure thing. Okay.
- 能o我看看你的{C - 好的
Can I see your driver's license?  Yeah.
@...
Yeah...
好的
Okay.
比奇伍德 很棒的小
Beachwood. Nice town.
是的 但...
Yes. But, um...
我搬走了
We've moved.
我搬去x我鹤痈近的住了
We live closer to my son.
你拿我的{C质颤N
What are you doing with my license?
我在把你的信息入FBI的背景{查
I'm entering your information into the FBI background check database.
噢
Oh.
他在{查什N
What do they look for?
一大堆Y料 看你是否橐驯欢ㄗ锏闹匦谭
A bunch of stuff.Whether you're a convicted felon,
涉嫌暴力犯罪
if you've been involved in a crime of violence,
被徒涿饴
dishonorably discharged from the army,
是否智力健全 或者是否^去五年
mentally competent.If you've got more than one DUI offense
不止一次酒{ 是否是逃犯
in the last five years,if you're a fugitive,
- 或者最近被指控重罪 - 逃犯?
or currently charged with a felony.  Fugitive?
是的 比如你在逃法律的制裁
Yeah, like, if you're running from the law.
你X得我看起硖拥
Do I look like I can run?
好吧 o你看些小一c的手
Uh, okay. Let me show you some of our smaller handguns.
我有M有 西格B M1911 格洛克（均槭型）
We got everything.SIG Sauers, 1911s, Glocks,
p
single action, double action.
- 先生 你懂 - ~...
Sir, do you know much about guns?  Um...
- 不懂 怎N了 - 那]PS
No. Why?     It's all right.
我@什N型的都有
We get all types in here.
好吧 新手的...
Uh, okay. Beginners...
通常是用c22口降
usually go with a .22.
它很p 易上手 後坐力很小
It's light. Easy to use.Very little recoil.
我X得@就是我朋友建h的
I think that's what my friend suggested.
好吧 依我砜
Okay. In my opinion,
你Ic22就相於碛辛艘话
you might as well get yourself a BB gun if you get a .22.
嘿 我不是在行推N 但多花500K
Look, I'm not trying to give you the hard sell, but $500 more,
你能碛幸话颜嬲有制幽芰Φ
you can get yourself a gun with real stopping power.
@是格洛克17 9mm手
Now this is a 9mm Glock 17.
格洛克? @是德
Glock? It is German, no?
接近正_答案了 它a自W地利
You're in the right neighborhood.Manufactured in Austria.
@是世界上最流行的谭ㄊ 不e吧
That's the most popular law enforcement pistol in the world. Okay?
它的後坐力非常小 所以不到手
It's got very little recoil so probably won't hurt your hand
但它肯定到入侵者
but it'll definitely hurt the intruder.
@好用
Is it easy to use?
但
I hope!
是的 它很易
Yeah, it's simple.
好吧 但是...
Yeah, but...
不知你介不介意 可不可以
Would you mind, could you...
臀使用f明
write down the instructions for me?
然可以 我的意思是 我可以示o你看怎N使用
Uh, sure. I mean,I can show you how to use it.
不了 那是很好 但拜了 臀下戆
No, that would be good.But please, write it down for me.
我有r候健忘
Sometimes I forget things.
客至上 @]}
Yeah, we all do, right?That's no problem.
好的 一切都妥了
Okay, you're good to go.
我去拿支P 然後
I'll grab a pen, and um...
湍下使用f明
write it all down for you.
- 古特曼先生 -  古特曼
Mr. Guttman?    Guttman. Yeah...
你怎N知道
How did you know?
你朋友早些r候打^f你快到了
Your friend called earlier and said you'd be arriving soon.
房g已槟浜昧
Your room's all ready for you.
房g是
We have you in...
125 就著走廊走
125. Just down the hall.
- 我付多少X - 已付^了
How much do I owe?  It's all taken care of,
包括附加M
including incidentals.
α 你朋友的要求 我槟阌了明天早上的出租
Oh, and I booked your taxi for the morning,like your friend asked.
xx你
Thank you.
- 喂? - 喂
Hello?  Hello.
- 煞 - 是我
Zev?    Yeah.
我是R克斯
It's Max.
我指示了酒店一些事
I gave the hotel some instructions.
- 你好 - 是的我好 R克斯
Are you okay?  Yes, yes, I'm okay, Max.
你拿到了
And you got the gun?
嗯 拿到了
Yeah, yeah.
很好 很好
Good. Good.
你知道做什N的
You know what to do.
照好自己 知道
Just take care of yourself, yeah?
晚安好 R克斯
You have a good night, Max.
晚安 煞
Good night, Zev.
露z?
Ruth?
你把舸蜷_好
Turn on the lights, please.
太黑了 我看不...
It's dark in here. I can't...
看不清楚
I can't see.
- 你好 - 嗨
Hello.        Hi.
迪・焯m德在家
Is Rudy Kurlander home?
在家 他在窍
Yeah. He is downstairs.
你是...
Are you...
迪・焯m德?
Rudy Kurlander?
是
Yes.
我是迪・焯m德
I'm Rudy Kurlander.
你是?
Who are you?
你可以...呃...
Can you, uh...
把P掉
turn off the television?
我JR你
Do I know you?
F在 你...
Now, please...
站到窗襞赃
stand by the window.
你是l
Who are you?
站到窗襞赃
Stand by the window.
如果你不告V我你是l有你磉@旱脑因
I am not going to do anything until you tell me
我什N都不做
who you are and why you're here.
咱是e了
Let us not argue.
站到窗去
Just stand by the window.
F在又要做什N
Now what?
得亮堂些我才能看清你的
I need to see light on your face.
- 把^D^去 - 你是l
Turn your head.        Who are you?
e吼
Don't yell.
拜 不要吼
Please, don't yell.
按我f的做 抬起^
Do as I say. Turn your head.
你是德人
Are you German?
是的
Yeah.
- 你也是德人? (德Z) - 是
You are also German?        Ja.
你多少q了
How old are you?
88 Eighty-eight.
你曾在德服役
Were you in the German army?
你在Y做什N
What did you do?
- 那都^去了 - 英Z f英Z
It is in the past.        English. Please, English.
- 我不喜gf德Z - 那都是70年前了
I do not like to speak German.        It's seventy years ago.
我那r太年p
I was very young-
回答我的}
Answer the question.
你是q太人?
Are you a Jew?
]e
Yeah.
- 你r在W斯S辛集中I - 我不在
Were you at Auschwitz?        No!
我都@q盗 有必要撒e
We are too old for lies.
在Y束前
I didn't know about Auschwitz
我都不知道W斯S辛集中I的事
until after the war.
我r在北非
I was in North Africa.
和隆美元一起
With General Rommel.
- 你有C - 有
You have proof?        Yes.
就在那
Over there.
我成槊公民的r候 移民局的官T我
When I became a US citizen, the immigration officer asked me
是否曾和{粹政府
if I had ever associated
有P
with the Nazi government of Germany
或者是否曾在集中I工作
or worked at a concentration camp.
我的回答f
I told the officer what I'll tell you.
是的 我效忠於我的家 我是一名人
Yes, I served for my country. I was a soldier.
我樽约荷榈人而自豪 所有人都樽约旱家而自豪
I was a proud German and that's what the men did.
我仍然槲家作出的I感到自豪
I'm still proud of my service.
@是隆美元
That's Rommel.
至於q太人
As far as the Jews...
我K不P心q太人 我J橄Ｌ乩帐Φ
I didn't care about the Jews. I thought Hitler was right.
q太人o我家砹颂多麻
They caused many problems for the country.
我J槲是在逐他 或是把他安置在IY...
I thought we were deporting them or putting them in work camps...
而不是像他所做的那
Not what they did.
那太可u了
It was shameful,
但我]有做那些事
but that was not me.
- 喂? - 是R克斯
Hello?        Is this Max?
是我
Yes.
我是煞
This is Zev.
呃... 不是...
Uh... It was...
不是他
not him.
- 你_定 - 我_定
Are you sure?        Yeah, I'm sure.
那你必要^m
Then you must go on.
必履行
You must do
你曾承Z^的
what you said you would.
近些年硪恢庇髀
There have been rumors for years
一些W斯S辛集中IY的hl官
that a number of Auschwitz SS officers
在接近尾的r候
stole the identities of executed prisoners
冒名替了被死的q太人的身份
near the end of the war.
在我中L後不久
Shortly after my stroke,
有C表明 一名W斯S辛集中I官
evidence was found that an Auschwitz Blockfuhrer
於19世o40年代牡移民
emigrated from Germany in the 1940s
K且最可能用假名迪・焯m德
and was most likely living under the name
^m生活
Rudy Kurlander.
西蒙・S森塔中心(西蒙・S森塔中心是一Hq太人嘟M @M是榱思o念{粹在二次世界大鹬斜⒌莫q太人而成立的)
The Simon Wiesenthal Center
找到了四名在那r期移民至此的
has found four Rudy Kurlanders
迪・焯m德
who emigrated during that period.
然而 ]有足虻淖C
However, there is not enough proof
逮捕他其中任何一人
to arrest any of them.
他的真名是W托・瓦利施
His real name is Otto Wallisch.
你必要找到他
You must find him.
我正在ふ椅腋赣H 他已⒔90q了
I'm looking for my father. He's almost 90 years old.
他的名字叫煞
His name is Zev.
我在ふ椅业母赣H
I'm looking for my father.
他90q了
He's 90 years old.
他滋烨巴獬鲩f逛
He went wandering a few days ago.
他的名字是煞颉す盘芈
His name is Zev Guttman.
我不知道他是否S身yЯ丝梢宰C明身份的C件
I don't know if he has any identification on him,
我甚至不_定他是否得自己的姓名
or... I don't even know if he remembers his name.
我想知道有]有人被送Mt院
I've been wondering if anybody has been brought into the hospital.
你X得我]缶
Do you not think I've already called the police?
女士先生
Ladies and gentlemen,
我快到加拿大境了
we're approaching the Canadian border,
到r候大家都需要下接受z查
at which point, we're all gonna have to get off the bus for inspection.
如果您能提前浜媚的o照或其他旅行C件
If you can have your passports and any travel documents ready,
⒐省不少rg xx合作
it'll make the process a lot faster. Thank you.
出示申
Declaration card?
您此行的目的是?
Purpose of your trip?
拜L一位朋友
To see a friend.
您朋友的姓名是?
What's your friend's name?
- 迪・焯m德 - 他住哪
Rudy Kurlander.       Where does he live?
福伊・德斯...福伊...
Foyer Des... Foyer...
- 我能看看 - 然可以
Can I see that?        Yeah, of course.
- 福伊・德斯先者B老院? - 是的
Foyer Des Pionniers Nursing Home?        Yeah.
您⑷胱“泊舐允『账固氐幕屎笃旅^?
And you'll be staying at the Queen's Motel in Hearst, Ontario?
]e
That's right.
您⒃诩幽么笸Ａ舳嗑
How long will you be in Canada?
大概赏戆
Two nights. Maybe.
o照
Passport?
先生 您的o照^期了
Sir, your passport's expired.
- ^期了? -
It is?        Yeah.
您有{照
Do you have a driver's license?
噢 然有
Oh, of course.
稍等
Hang on a second.
好了 您可以走了
Alright, you're good to go.
不^您⒆o照延期
But, sir, renew your passport.
我都@q盗 用不著了
I didn't think it was necessary at my age.
祝您c朋友相聚愉快
Have fun with your friend.
xx
Thank you.
打_一下
Excuse me.
需要什N椭 先生
How can I help you, sir?
迪・焯m德在哪房g
Rudy Kurlander. Which room is he in?
焯m德?
Kurlander?
焯m德 他在238房
Yes, Kurlander. He's in room 238.
沿著@l走廊走 坐梯
Just go down this hallway and take the elevators.
出梯後 左D 再右D
When you exit the elevator, make a left, then you take a right.
238房就在你的左手
238 will be on your left.
明白了
Did you get that?
我直接您去您朋友的房g吧
Why don't I just show you where your friend's room is?
xx
Thank you.
你是迪・焯m德
Are you Rudy Kurlander?
迪・焯m德?
Rudy Kurlander?
我是
Here.
- 你是迪・焯m德? - 是的
Are you Rudy Kurlander?        Yeah.
你是德人
Are you German?
是的
Yes.
你以前在W斯S辛集中I
Were you at Auschwitz?
是的
Yes.
我去^W斯S辛集中I
I was at Auschwitz.
我全家人都在
My whole family was
W斯S辛集中I
murdered
被⒘
at Auschwitz.
我感到很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
你很...很抱歉?
You're... you're sorry?
]e
Yeah.
你的所作所椴皇堑歉就足虻
What you did is something you cannot apologize for.
我l^誓我⑺
I swore I would kill the man responsible
⒑ξ胰家性命的那人
for the death of my family.
你是q太人?
You're Jewish?
我是同性
Homosexual.
是我道歉才
It is I who am sorry.
Σ黄 真的很抱歉
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry!
莫什科夫斯基
Moszkowski.
你知道莫什科夫斯基?
You know Moszkowski?
我以前的琴老曾f
My old piano teacher used to say
三位最ゴ蟮淖髑家分e是
that the three greatest composers
T德松 梅耶
were Mendelssohn, Meyerbeer
以及莫什科夫斯基
and Moszkowski.
- 你F在 - 噢...
Do you still play?        Oh...
不
No.
不 我不知道 我不_定
No, I don't know, I'm not sure!
那N...
Well...
槭颤N不呢
Why don't you give it a try?
噢... 好吧...
Oh... Well...
T德松
Mendelssohn.
大概吧
Maybe.
你好 先生 g迎淼讲┮廖
Hello, sir. Welcome to Boise.
您A定^了
Do you have a reservation?
我@有您早上8c需要出租服
I have a note that you need a taxi pickup at 8:00 am.
我㈧6c起供免M早餐
So, we have our complimentary breakfast which starts at 6:00 a.m.
如果您街贝┻^左手的大d...
And if you just head through the lobby to your left...
我椭您 好
Here, let me help you, okay?
有件事 我忘了б路了
There is one thing. I forgot to pack more clothes.
- Q洗的衣服 - 噢
Extra clothes.        Oh!
@完全不是}
We can definitely help you out with that.
每整c都有一趟公共汽奈@Yl往市中心
So, there's a downtown shuttle that leaves every hour on the hour
@趟⒛送到北密沃基路的商
and it's going to drop you right off at the mall on North Milwaukee street.
您可以在那I到您需要的所有|西
You should be able to get everything you need there...
先生 你需要我湍A
Sir, would you like me to do that?
先生 您好
Sir, are you okay?
您F在想去您的房g了 好勒
Would you like to head up to your room now? Okay.
- 您需要我湍阏沂颤N - 噢 是的
Can I help you find anything?        Oh, yes.
我想I一件新r衫
I want to buy a new shirt.
我有很多短袖系扣r衫
We have a great deal on short-sleeve button downs.
- 是 - 您要看看
Yeah?        Can I show you?
- 隈{ - 不客
Thank you.        Yeah.
季末的r候最划算了
You can always find the best deals at the end of the season.
好的
Oh, right.
抱歉 先生 您|了警
Excuse me, sir. You set off the alarm.
我得z查一下您的包
I'm gonna have to check your bag.
噢 我看起硐\
Oh. Do I look like a thief?
噢 跟@]PS 先生 您|了警
Oh, it doesn't matter, sir, you set off the alarm.
不管怎游叶嫉z查一下您的包
I've got to check your bag no matter what, so...
@是收
There's the receipt.
噢 }在@
Oh, there's your problem right there.
他忘把安全嘶`取下了
They left the security tag on.
我得z查一下您另外一包 先生
I'll have to check your other bag too, sir.
@是一把格洛克
Is that a Glock?
是啊
Yeah.
我想起了我第一把
Reminds me of my first gun.
祝您今天^得愉快 先生
You have a good day, sir.
- o您 非常感x - xx xx
There you go. Thanks very much.        Thank you. Thank you...
您要m杯
Would you like a refill?
- 好的 xx - 不客
Yes. Thank you.        You're very welcome.
你能告V我倪@旱讲剪Z有多h
Could you tell me how far is Bruneau is from here?
我]去^布Z 不^那是在W严？
I've never actually been to Bruneau, but it's in Owyhee County,
所以 我X得大概是三四十分的路程吧
so, I'd say that should probably take you about 30, 40 minutes or so.
- 噢 - 我f那旱泥l下很漂亮
Oh.        I heard it's beautiful country down there.
我]去^但是我朋友...
I never get to go but my friends...
- 噢 - 啊
Oh!        Ah.
噢 我很抱歉
Oh, I'm so sorry!
- 我把咖啡撒到你的信上了 - 噢 天啊
I got coffee on your letter.        Oh, God.
住手 你把我的信Я
No, you're ruining my letter!
- 不要 不要 不要 - 我很抱歉
No, no, no!        I'm sorry.
@封信很重要 住手 住手 住手
This letter is very important! Stop! Stop! Stop!
除了我
"Besides me,
你是唯一一
"you are the only person
仍然能J出
"who can still recognize
那人L相的人
"the face of the man
他⒑α宋的家人
"who murdered our families."
- ]人在家 - ]有
Nobody's home?        No.
您想我把您送到其他地方
You want me to take you somewhere else?
- 不不不 我再等等 - o您
No, no, no. I will wait.        Here.
您什Nr候需要我回斫幽就o我打
Give me a call whenever you want me to come back and get you.
我付你多少X
What do I owe you?
噢 您已付^X了 得
Oh, you already paid me, remember?
如果你需要乘o我打就行
Just call me if you need a ride later.
早安
Morning.
你也早安 小可
Morning to you too, sweetie.
]e...
Yeah...
吃晚了 谏U姆先生
Dinner time, Mr. Rosenbaum.
o我c吃的 可以
Bring me back some food, yeah?
您_定 您已在房gY待了一整天了
Are you sure? You haven't been outside the apartment all day.
- 我_定 - 好吧
Yes.        Okay.
我能湍什N
Can I help you with something?
我碚音迪・焯m德
I'm looking for Rudy Kurlander.
呃 您Φ胤搅 但是...
Well, you came to the right place but, uh...
我的爸爸3月前去世了
My old man passed away about three months ago.
噢 我不知道@ 我很z憾
Oh, I didn't know this. I am so sorry.
您在@旱攘硕嗑昧
How long have you been waiting here?
一整天
All day.
您要喝c什N
You want a drink?
那好O了
A drink would be nice.
M戆
Come on in.
我自己也睃c
I could use another drink myself.
- xx你 - 要啤酒是水
Thank you.        Beer or a water?
水就可以了 xx你
Just water, please.
哦 伊娃 乖 e叫了
Oh, Eva. Good girl. Good girl.
著 我有c怕狗
Listen, I am a little scared of dogs.
伊娃不咬人的 M戆
Eva's all bark and no bite.Come on in.
我相信你 但我是U害怕的
But I'm sure that's true but I'm... I'm quite scared.
哦 我把它ё ]}的
Oh, I'll put her away for you. Okay.
我走 好拥
Here we go. Good girl.
e叫了 伊娃
Quiet, girl. Eva!
伊娃 u 安o
Eva, shush, quiet.
安o e叫了 伊娃 u
Girl, quiet. Calm down, Eva. Shush.
伊娃 u u
Eva, shush. Shush.
伊娃 安o下 安o
Eva, calm down now. Calm down.
e叫了
Quiet!
那是我鹤拥漠I照
That's my, um, kid's graduation.
我父H一直很喜g那照片
Dad always loved that photo.
- 我去...拿水o你 - 好的
- I'm gonna get... grab your water for you. - Yeah.
@照片什Nr候拍的  你父H看起砗苣贻p
When was that taken? Your father looks so young.
那是 ~ 1997拍的
That was, uh, in 1997.
- 哦 - Π 老益 不是
- Oh. - Yeah. Dad aged well, didn't he?
1997 1997.
他一直f他是焯m德家族基因最好的
He always said that he was one of the Kurlanders with good genes.
o你
Here you go.
哦 你比伊娃渴
Oh, you were thirstier than Eva.
- 要 - 好的 xx你
- Another one? - Oh, please.
然後就不再麻┠懔
And then I won't bother you again.
不 不的 完全不麻
Oh, no, no. It's no bother at all.
你要待多久都可以
Stay as long as you like.
自...我父H去世了 一人住在@Y很孤
Ever since, uh... since Dad died, it's been pretty lonely out here.
你知道 我就一直在附近巡
You know, I'm just driving around
除了V播 偶被{派 ]e的事了
doing my rounds, with nothing but the radio and the occasional dispatch.
回家r有人能跟我ff真好
It's good to have someone to talk to when I come home.
伊娃很棒 但她竟不能跟我聊天
Eva's great and all，but not much for conversation.
- 你要的水 - 你]Y婚?
- Here's your water. - You're not married?
不 不是的 坐 我Y^婚...纱
No, no. Have a seat. I was, you know, twice.
第一老婆 ё吡宋业姆孔
The first one, uh, took my house,
第二老婆 在袷鍪召
the second one left before...
@套房子之前x_了
...the quarry takes this one.
那是...哇 七年前的事了
That was...Ooh, hell, seven years already.
我不介意再找一
I wouldn't mind getting another one,
但布Z不是最m合紊淼娜说牡胤
but Bruneau ain't exactly the best singles scene
而我 也不是S金紊h
and, well, I ain't exactly the best single.
你爸爸跟你起^德
Did your father ever talk to you about Germany?
你在_玩笑
Are you kidding me?
他]停止^德
He never stopped talking about Germany.
他有]有跟你f^P於二鸬氖?
Did he ever speak to you about the war?
然
Of course.
你知道他是收集狂吧?
You know he was a collector, right?
啊
Ah.
我有一堆他的|西 你想看看
I got a bunch of his stuff. You wanna go take a look?
好啊
Yeah.
小心台A 就在@Y
Watch your step. Just come down here.
伊娃 安o 伊娃 u
Eva, quiet! Eva, shh.
嘿 著 ~ @Y有cy
Hey, listen, uh, it's kind of a mess in here.
我得把箱子挪_ 然後
Let me just move some boxes and I'll...
我你去另一房g
I'll let you in the other room.
@
Here we go.
倪@Y 好的 戆 哦
There we go. There. Come on. Oh!
M戆
Come on in.
那是 ~ 那是我爸爸的傲和快
That was, uh...that was Dad's pride and joy.
那uo我的人l誓1938年11月19日@面旗迷诎亓诛w舞
The dealer he bought it from swore it was flying in Berlin on November 19, 1938.
水晶之夜
Kristallnacht.
Π 水晶之夜
Kristallnacht... Yeah.
父H曾f @面旗
Dad used to say that that flag, um,
C了v史的_端
witnessed the beginning of history.
你知道
You know?
- 箱子Y有什N? - ~ 就是
- What is in these boxes?  - Uh, just...
一些父H得到的其他p 你知道
a bunch more of Dad's prize pieces. You know?
我已u掉了大部分的收藏
I already sold most of the collection
但是 @些是跟他有感情的
but, uh, these are the things he was sentimental about.
B我也]k法u了它 你知道
Just haven't been able to let myself get rid of 'em, you know?
你想到看看
You wanna look around?
- 感x - ]PS
- Thank you. - Yeah.
@是初刊本
Yeah, that was a first printing.
有人想用6000美元跟我I 但我就是]k法...u掉它
A guy offered me six grand for it but I just... just couldn't part with it.
我猜我跟我父H一痈星橛檬 Π
I guess I'm just as sentimental as my old man, huh?
你可以S便在周看看...任何|西都可以
You're welcome to look around at... at anything you like.
我去鸵镣渌的晚餐
I'm just gonna give Eva her dinner.
安o u
Quiet! Shh!
or之 Π
Priceless, right?
Π
Yeah.
我想我不把它像那尤在箱子Y面
I guess I shouldn't leave it stuffed in a box like that.
你想要再喝c什N
You want another drink?
好的 那很好
Yes. That would be good.
再硪槐水 是烈一c的|西
More water,or something a little stronger?
烈一c的好了
Maybe something a little stronger.
好的
All right.
F在你知道我在f什N了
Now you're speaking my language.
是啊...
Yeah...
敬我父H
To Dad.
你知道 我爸他...
You know, my dad was, uh...
我爸那天晚上在那
My dad was there that night.
- 哪晚上 - ~ 水晶...
- What night was that? - Um, Kristal...
- 水晶之夜 -  水晶之夜
- Kristallnacht. - Yeah. Kristallnacht.
他f他Я艘FN
Yeah, he said he had a hammer
他打碎了一些珠店的窗
and he broke a bunch of jewelry store windows.
- 他跟你f^@件事 - ]有
- He ever tell you that story? - No.
]有?
No?
我真希望你在他活著的r候磉@Y
I so wish you were here when he was still alive.
你知道 每^一段rg 有一些他的朋友^
You know, every once in a while, some of his buddies would come by
他就坐在@Y f一些故事 喝喝酒 你知道
and they'd just sit around, tell stories, drink, you know?
他很喜gv一些以前的事
He loved to talk about the old days.
你好 你流了很多汗
You okay? You're sweating there.
- 哦 我有c - 把你的外套了吧
- Oh, I feel a little hot. Yes. - Well, take your jacket off.
戆
Come here. Mmm.
把你的外套了 然後 我只是想要告V你
Yeah, take your jacket off and, hey, I just want to tell you something.
- 我求之不得你能... - 哦
- You are more than welcome... - Oh.
...在@Y住一晚 如果你不介意睡在我父H的f床上
...to spend the night if you like, if you don't mind sleeping in dad's old bed.
- 你人真好 不必了 xx你 - 不 不
- You're very kind. No, thank you.  - No, no.
- 好吧 反正我的提hSr有效 - 哦 xx你
- Well, all right, the offer's on the table. - Oh, thank you.
父H的朋友就是我的朋友
Any friend of Dad's is a friend of mine.
你怎NJR他的 你曾跟他一起服役?
How'd you know him? Did you serve with my dad?
- 不是 - 好吧 那你怎NJR他的
- No. - Well, how did you know him then?
我在W斯S辛JR他的
I knew him from Auschwitz.
W斯S辛?
Auschwitz?
我父H很希望他能在W斯S辛服役
My dad wished he served at Auschwitz.
你是f你父H]去^W斯S辛?
You mean your father was not at Auschwitz?
你在f什N...
What are you...
你是J真的 我父H是的N
Are you serious? My dad was a cook in the army.
他不是集中II袖? He was not a Blockfuhrer?
我都不知道那是什N 不是 我父H在_始的r候才10q
I don't even know what that is. No, my dad was 10 when the war started.
德人他做的最多的事就是 你知道
Most that the Germans let him do was, you know,
打破一些窗 煮一些S也{炸牛排 你知道
break a bunch of windows and cook some Wiener Schnitzel, you know?
很抱歉打_你了
I am sorry to have bothered you.
- 我找e人了 - 不 ]事的 哇 哇塞
- I have the wrong Rudy Kurlander. - No, no, no. Whoa. Whoa. Whoa.
等一下 你以前在W斯S辛?
Wait a minute, you were at Auschwitz?
- 嗯 - ]有一我爸的朋友在那Y服役
- Oh. - None of my dad's buddies served at a camp.
我必x_了 我已打_你很久了
I must leave you now. I have bothered you enough.
打_我? 不 ]有 留下
Bothered me? No, no, no. Please stay.
留下 分享一些故事吧
Please stay. Share some stories.
我再去拿一瓶酒 我就...
I'll grab another bottle. We'll just...
那是什N
What's that?
What is that?
那他的是什N
What the fuck is that?
~...Σ黄 我...
Well... I'm sorry. I...
我 ~...
I, uh...
那他的是什N
What the fuck is that?
你是q太人?
Are you a Jew?
是的
Yeah.
你是一q太人?
You're a Jew?
F在他是怎N回事
What the fuck's going on here?
Σ黄 我...
I'm sorry, I...
干你娘 o我坐下
Sit the fuck down.
拜你 我走吧
Please, let me go.
你他在我家
What the fuck are you doing in my house?
我搞e了 你父H不是我要找的人
I made a mistake. Your father is the wrong man.
我父H?
My father?
你f你是我父H的朋友
You said you were a friend of my dad.
你_我
You lied to me.
- 我]有fe 我]有fe - 干你娘u掰
- I did not lie. I did not lie! - Jesus fucking Christ.
你f你是我父H的朋友 你到我家Y
You said you were a friend of my dad, you come into my house
他的喝我的威士忌
and you drink my fucking whiskey,
而你他是一av的q太人
and you're a dirty fucking Jew.
伊娃 ]上你的狗嘴
Eva, shut the fuck up!
e吼了 求你了 e再吼了 我走
Stop yelling! Please, stop yelling! I will go.
你o我坐下
Sit the fuck down!
你他F在立刻回答我的}
You gotta answer some questions right fucking now!
操你的 你是尿在了我的沙l上
Holy shit! Did you just piss on my couch?
- Σ黄 我很抱歉 - 操你
- I'm sorry. I'm so sorry. - What the fuck?
e再叫了
Stop yelling!
伊娃 你他]嘴
Eva, shut the fuck up!
你是在命令我 q太人
Are you giving me a fucking order, Jew?
伊娃 我你]嘴 你知道...
Eva, I said, "Shut the fuck up!" You know...
你知道如果我父H知道他有一q太人在他家他f什N
you know what my dad would say if he knew a fucking Jew was in his house, huh?
他f "希特勒他的fq"
He would say, "Heil fucking Hitler."
]e 那就是他f的
That's what he'd say. Yeah.
希特勒他的fq! 希特勒fq! 希特勒fq!
Heil fucking Hitler! Heil Hitler! Heil Hitler!
希特勒fq! 希特勒fq 你他的q太人!
Heil Hitler! Heil Hitler, you fucking Jew!
伊娃 死的 o我安o
Eva, goddamn it, shut the fuck up!
]嘴 你有什N}啊
Shut up! What's your problem?
哈? ]嘴
Huh? Shut up!
停下 伊娃 安o
Stop it! Eva, quiet!
伊娃
Eva!
死 ]嘴 ]嘴 操你 安o
Damn it, shut up! Shut up, damn it! Quiet!
伊娃 冷o下
Eva, settle down.
你他想要去活生生的q太人
You want to meet a real life fucking Jew?
哈 是
Huh? Huh?
哈 去抓他吧
Huh? Go get him.
啊!
Ah!
我操你...
What the...
你@死的q太人
You fucking kike!
我操...
You fucking...
哦...
Oh...
@是s翰・焯m德
You've reached John Kurlander.
留言吧 如果有急事 打我的手C
Leave me a message. Or if it's an emergency, call my cell phone.
露z?
Ruth?
s翰 你在哪 你已晚了半小r了
Where you at, John? You're a half hour late
我不能整早上都湍阊谧o
and I can't cover your ass all morning.
- 我l誓 你最好是出了... - 你在f什N
- I swear, you best be having car trouble... - What are you saying?
我的天啊
My God.
哦...
Oh...
你好
Hello.
- R克思 我是煞 - 你去哪了
- Max, it's Zev. - Where have you been?
我⒘艘人
I killed a man.
~...
Uh...
F在是最y的部分了 你必缶
Now is the hardest part. You must call the police.
- 你必... - 不 不是的
- You must... - No, no!
他不是我要找的人
He was not the man we are looking for.
- 那是l - 一年p很多的男人
- Who was he? - It was a much younger man.
我 ~... 在一箱子上看到了他的名字
I, uh... I saw his name on a box.
他叫做s翰・焯m德
It was John Kurlander.
他是一{粹
He is a Nazi.
- 你怎N知道的 - 有很多{粹的|西
- How do you know this? - There were many Nazi things
- 在房gY 有很多|西 - 哦
- in the house. Many things. - Oh.
@不是我的初衷
This is not what we set out to do.
煞
Zev.
你想^m
Do you want to continue?
我想 我必完成
Yes, I must finish.
我必
I must.
竟 那是⒘宋全家的人
After all, this is the man who killed our families.
露z?
Ruth?
露z!
Ruth!
喂
Hello.
我是
Yes.
哦 我的天啊 xx你 太感x你了
Oh, my God. Thank you. Thank you so much.
他好
Is he okay?
不 他有V呆
No, he has dementia. Mm-hmm.
不好意思 ~
I'm sorry. Uh...
你是哪难Y打淼? 我R上^去
Where are you calling from? I can be there right away.
YZo念t院?
Reno Memorial Hospital?
- YZ 热A_州? - YZ?
- Reno, Nevada? - Reno?
我可以跟我父Hv
Is it possible that I could speak with my father?
好的 xx 非常感x你
Yeah, thank you. Thank you very much.
夥 我要打嚏了
Guys, I gotta sneeze.
喂
Hello.
哦 你好啊 查斯
Oh, hello, Charles.
是啊 哦 我很好 e心
Yeah. Yeah, no, I'm fine. I'm fine.
xx你
Thank you.
我叫t生e去打_你
I told the doctors not to bother you.
哈
Huh?
你e心我了
Please, don't you worry about me.
哦 不 不用的 你e磲t院
No. No. No. Don't you come to the hospital.
你母H斫游业
Your mother will pick me up.
你跟她一起?
Maybe you come with her, huh?
Π 我很好 ]事的 嗯 好的 再
Yeah, I'm fine. I'm fine. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Goodbye. Goodbye.
你喜g卡通?
Do you like cartoons?
我喜g迪士尼l道的
I like Disney Channel.
- 米老鼠 - 不是 我喜gw哥c小佛
- Mickey Mouse? - No. I like Phineas and Ferb.
哦
Oh.
我]f^他
I never heard of them.
莫利 我R上回
I'll be right back, Molly.
你快做你的功n吧
You finish your homework please.
- 你叫莫利? - 莫利・伊莎白
- Your name is Molly? - Molly Elizabeth.
你喜g糖果 莫利・伊莎白
Do you like sweets, Molly Elizabeth?
好的 ~
Well, uh...
我想我的大衣口袋Y有一些硬糖
I think there are some caramels in my coat pocket.
我一直槲业O子湟恍┰谀茄Y
I always keep some there for my grandchildren.
啊
Ah.
我找不到
I can't find any.
好吧 我妻子淼r候б恍┑
Well, my wife will bring some when she comes.
- 你是煞 - 是的
- Are you Zev? - Yes.
我能看你的信
Can I open your letter?
可以啊
Uh-huh.
- 哇 你真有X - 什N?
- Whoa, you're rich! - What?
l是R克思
Who's Max?
R克思?
Max?
我不清楚
I'm not sure.
等等 要不然你把信xo我吧
Wait. Why don't you read the letter to me out loud?
"煞 有些事令人y以接受 可你得知道"
"Zev, there are some difficult things you must know."
"首先 露z已^世了"
"Firstly, Ruth has passed away."
"她得了癌Y"
"She had cancer."
"她勰 在她最後的r刻 你陪在她身 握著她的手"
"She loved you and you were with her, holding her hand, at the end."
"其次 你患有V呆Y"
"Secondly, you have dementia."
"最近你得健忘了"
"Recently you have been forgetting many things."
那很正常 老年人是弁事
That's normal. Old people always forget things.
是啊 是啊
Yeah. Yeah.
"我有著相似的v"
"You and I have a similar history."
"我都是W斯S辛..."
"We are both Auschwitz..."
- W斯S辛 W斯S辛 - "W斯S辛的存者"
Auschwitz. Auschwitz.        "Auschwitz survivors."
"看看你的左臂 你是98814囚犯"
"Look at your left arm, you were prisoner 98814."
"Y束r"
"When the war ended,"
"我承Z自己"
"I promised myself"
"我要找到那些榇素的人"
"I would find the men responsible."
"c西蒙・威森塔共事期g"
"Working with Simon Wiesenthal,"
"我兔ψカ@了大批前'{'分子"
"I have helped to capture dozens of former Nazis"
"他遍咽澜绺鞯"
"all around the world."
- '{'是什N       - 是{粹 {粹
What's a Nazi?        Nazi. Nazi.
一N娜
A bad person.
六月前 上帝n我好\
Six months ago, God smiled upon me
你搬到高社^後
when you moved to the senior housing community.
我立刻就J出了那曾在W斯S辛的你
I immediately recognized you from Auschwitz,
管你已不得我
although you did not remember me.
我是那z^健在的最後的存者
We are the last living survivors from our prison block.
除我之外 你是唯一一
Besides me, you are the only person
能J出⒑ξ家人的词置婵椎娜
who could still recognize the face of the man who murdered our families.
西蒙・威森塔猿终J
Simon Wiesenthal insisted
所有鸱付受到公_判
that all war criminals be given public trials.
但是 我不能o瓦利施@C
However, we cannot give Wallisch that opportunity.
管C_
Even if there was enough proof,
他 跟我一 很可能
he, like us, would probably die
在被引渡德之前已去世
before he could be extradited to Germany.
我都同 W托・瓦利施必死
We have agreed that Otto Wallisch must die.
你必⒘怂
You must kill him.
"你答等露z去世你就去"
"You promised to go once Ruth died.
"你答了我 你也答了露z"
"You promised me and you promised Ruth."
你x得很棒
You did a very good job.
xx
Thanks.
露z是l
Who's Ruth?
我的妻子
My wife.
我以樗能c糖果o我
I thought she was bringing me candy.
我也希望碇
I thought so, too.
我要去假日旅^
Yes, I need to go to Holiday Inn Express
塔霍湖大道3961
3961 Lake Tahoe Boulevard.
- 在湖南岸 -
South Lake?         Yeah.
那得一多小r
That's over an hour away.
- 哦 那... 我蝈X了 - 上吧
Oh, that's... I have money.        Hop in.
- 你好 煞? - 是的
Hello. Zev?        Yeah.
感x上帝
Thank God.
你在哪
Where are you?
煞?
Zev?
塔霍
Tahoe.
你明白你怎N做
You understand what you must do
只剩一人了
There's only one left.
是的 我明白
Yeah, I understand...
我怎N做
what I must do.
- 早 - 早上好
Morning.        Good morning.
我想退房
I'd like to check out, please.
xx你
Thank you.
- 你的手受了? - 哦  是的
You hurt your hand?        Oh, yes, yes.
- 它...好了 能 - 不e
It's... Well, I can move.        Good.
好的 共106美元20美分
Okay, that'll be $106.20.
我想搭出租的X是蛄
I think I will have enough money for the taxi.
哦 呃 我也能用信用卡的
Oh, uh, we take credit cards, too.
是啊
Yeah.
xx你
Thank you.
塔霍? 他在塔霍搞什N鬼
Tahoe? What the heck is he doing in Tahoe?
不 我正在租
No, I'm just picking up a rental now
我想我_^去
and I guess I'll just drive up there.
好
Yeah.
哦 著 你能著找到
Oh, look, can you try and find
他搭的那v出租所俟司的名字
the name of the taxi company that picked him up?
xx你
Thank you.
需要兔
Can I help you?
迪・焯m德 他在@住
Rudy Kurlander, he lives here?
- 是的 - 我能跟他聊聊
Yes.        Can I speak with him?
- 他在睡X - 哦
He's still sleeping.         Oh.
好吧 我能在@等他...醒
Well, could I wait for him to... wake up?
是要o事
It's important.
什N事啊
What's this about?
呃 是私事
Well, it's private.
而且他J得我 他J得我
And he knows me, he knows me.
我很久以前就JR他了
I knew him a long time ago.
- M戆 - 哦 xx你 xx你
Come on in.        Oh, thank you. Thank you.
- 需要肀咖啡 您叫... - 古特曼
Do you want a cup of coffee, Mr...        Guttman.
行 咖啡挺好 xx你
Yes, coffee would be nice. Thank you.
- 呃 黑咖啡就好 - 在客d坐
Uh, just black.        Take a seat in the living room.
我去煮咖啡
I've got a pot brewing.
那是我家啄昵爸鼐鄣r候照的
That's from our family reunion a couple years ago.
噢
Oh.
真是大家庭
You have a big family.
我父H壅f他生了一支足球
My father likes to say he fielded a soccer team.
我是老小
I'm his youngest.
你母H有多大
How old was your mother?
她年p多了 父H是二婚
She was a lot younger. It was his second marriage.
- xx你 - 古特曼先生 我能您}N
Thank you.        Can I ask you a question, Mr. Guttman?
您的事跟W斯S辛有PN
Does you being here have to do with Auschwitz?
是的
Yes.
我父H可不那事
My father's not gonna want to talk about that.
哦
Oh.
我理解
I understand.
您意跟我共M早餐 古特曼先生
Would you like to join us for breakfast, Mr. Guttman?
我做了些烤O果
I'm making baked apple pancakes.
我不太I 真是感x你
I'm not very hungry. Thank you very much.
我不打_你太久的
I won't bother you for long.
你_定? @可是家髅匮u
Are you sure? It's an old family recipe.
嗯 是的 我_定 可是xx你
Mmm. Yes, I am sure, but thank you just the same.
您等我下 我去告V父H您砹
If you'd excuse me, I am just going to run up and tell Dad you're here.
好 好的
Yeah, yeah.
呃 你是l
Uh, who are you?
哦 我是煞
Oh, I am Zev.
- 嗨 煞 - 英格
Hi, Zev.       Inge
那是l
Who is that?
那是你外公的老朋友
Well, it's an old friend of your grandfather.
你喜g瓦格{?
You like Wagner?
是啊 我一直都喜弁吒窦{
Yes. I have always loved Wagner.
我女赫f砹我JR的W斯S辛人
My daughter said someone I knew from Auschwitz was here.
但作橐存者不喜g瓦格{的 不是 (瓦格{ 德作曲家 N族主x者 反q太主x者)
But a survivor should not like Wagner, no?
音酚植豢珊
You can't hate music.
我 呃 ]能在那些照片中J出你
I, uh, didn't recognize your face in those pictures.
但是...
But...
你的音...
Your voice...
]
has not changed.
我知道有一天你碚椅
I knew you would come to find me one day.
外公 煞蚴悄闩笥
Zev's your friend, Poppy?
英格 你回N房去
Inge, please go back into the kitchen.
我得跟我朋友探些事
My friend and I need to discuss some things.
我]忘你
I have not forgotten you.
戆...我到外面去
Please... let us go outside.
我不想我的家人...我要f的事
I do not want my family to hear...what we have to say.
已有很久...
It has been a long time...
]人J出那暗奈伊
since anyone knew who I was.
我甚至不清有多久
I cannot even remember when.
@些年 人盯著我看
Over the years people have looked at me
我就以樗J出我了 其他]有
and I think they know, but they never do.
或S他只是太害怕 所以什N都不敢f
Or maybe they were just too scared to say anything.
有r候 我到@ f出自己的名字
Sometimes, I come out here and speak my name.
我自言自Z
I talk to myself.
重新回起以前的那我
I remind myself of who I was.
@是唯一一N我知道自己存在^的方式
It is the only way to know I existed...
在我成F在@人之前的那自我
before I became who I am now.
好吧 靠e言^活算什N人生
Well, living a lie is not a life.
我一直都知道你找到我
I always knew you would find me.
已^了太久
It has been too long.
F在我都是老人了
We are old men now.
把你的手拿_ W托
Take your hands off of me, Otto.
什N
Excuse me?
我f "把你的手拿_"
I said, "Take your hands off of me."
你叫我W托?
You called me Otto.
我想你弄糊T了
I think you're confused.
]有 你的名字叫W托・瓦利施
No, your name is Otto Wallisch.
你是W斯S辛的一zL You were a Blockfuhrer at Auschwitz.
你⒘宋业募胰
And you killed my family.
你了
Are you crazy?
你自欺欺人@N久
You've lived a lie for so long
你自己都信以檎媪
you've convinced yourself it is true.
我...
I...
我不明白
I do not understand.
那我湍
Let me help you...
弄明白
understand.
感X像我_了家旅^
It's like we're running a hotel.
去告V外公早好了
Go tell Pop-Pop breakfast is ready.
- 是l啊 - 我叫查斯・古特曼
Who is it?        My name's Charles Guttman.
我想我父H在@
I think my father's here.
嗨 真抱歉打_您
Hi, I'm so sorry to bother you,
可是我f不久前有v出租d我爸爸到@
but I was told that a taxi dropped my dad off here a little while ago.
是啊 他跟我父H在外面
Yeah, he's outside with my father.
感x上帝
Thank God.
他已失一周了
He's been missing for a week.
失?
Missing?
- y以置信 跟我 - xx
I had no idea. Come on.        Thank you.
- 爸? - 哦 上帝啊
Dad?        Oh, my God.
-  - eo
Mommy?        Please do not be frightened.
e害怕
Don't be scared.
爸 你槭颤N不 呃 把放低些
Dad, why don't you, uh, lower the gun?
- 查斯? - 啊
Charles?        Yeah.
- 你在@致 - 呃...
What are you doing here?       Uh...
爸 把放下
Dad, put the gun down.
- 把放下 爸 - 不 不
Put down the gun, Dad.        No. No.
除非他f出真相
Not until he tells the truth.
槭颤N你要@幼
Why are you doing this?
告V她你是l
Tell them who you are.
你el了
Please, stop this madness.
告V她你做了什N
Tell them what you did.
- 放^她 拜了 - f英Z
Leave them alone, please.        English!
我求你了
I beg you.
我要她懂你f的
I want them to understand what you're saying.
爸爸 他在f什N啊
Dad, what is he talking about?
e他的 他了
Do not listen to him. He is crazy!
是
Ach so?
你的x窈芎
You have a very easy choice.
你可以f出真相她活下
You can tell the truth and she lives,
你也可以撒e 然後看著她倒下
or you can lie and watch her die.
o你三秒
You have three seconds.
- 一 - 拜 e@
One.        Please stop.
- 二 - 求你了 朝我_吧
Two.        Please, just shoot me.
- 爸 停下 - 三
Dad, stop it!        Three.
好吧 好吧
Okay. Okay.
好吧
Okay.
在期g
During the war,
我不是囚犯
I was not a prisoner.
大c
Louder.
- 在期g我不是囚犯 - 再大c!
During the war I was not a prisoner.        Louder!
在期g我不是囚犯!
During the war I was not a prisoner!
我是{粹
I was a Nazi.
我是hl
I was SS.
我是W斯S辛集中I的一zL I was a Blockfuhrer at Auschwitz.
你⑦^人
Did you kill people?
是的
Yes.
-  你⑦^人? - 你⒘硕嗌偃
You killed people, Poppy?        How many people did you kill?
我不清楚
I don't know.
很多人
Many.
F在告V她你的真名
And now tell them your real name.
我的名字叫...
My name is...
炷岵特・斯德姆
Kunibert Sturm.
不
No.
你的名字叫瓦利施!
Your name is Wallisch!
不 就是炷岵特・斯德姆
No, it's Kunibert Sturm.
你叫W托・瓦利施!
You are Otto Wallisch!
不
No.
是你 你叫W托・瓦利施
You! You are Otto Wallisch!
你在撒e
You're lying.
]有
No.
@是70年砦业谝淮握f真
It's the first time I haven't lied in 70 years.
你才是W托・瓦利施
You are Otto Wallisch.
我是炷岵特・斯德姆 我都是W斯S辛的zL
I am Kunibert Sturm. We were both Blockfuhrers.
不...
No...
我是囚犯
I was a prisoner.
看看你的胳膊
Look at your arm.
你是98814 我是98813
You are number 98814. I am 98813.
是我互相y的 @是我唯一的逃生k法
We tattooed each other. It was our only way to escape.
爸?
Dad?
是真的
Is that true?
不 都是e言 都是e言
No, it's all lies. It's all lies.
@不是真的
It's not true.
e言?
Lies?
你怎N能忘呢
How could you forget?
你o自己取名叫煞 因樗是狼的意思
You took the name Zev because it means wolf.
你f我z都是狼
You said we were wolves!
哦 我的上帝
Oh, my God.
我得
I remember.
爸?
Dad?
爸
Dad!
F在 我在等待
Right now, we're still waiting
碜运霍湖警察局的消息
to hear from the Lake Tahoe Police Department.
他仍未向者透露或l压俜铰明
They haven't spoken to reporters or released a statement just yet.
但他向我保C
But they have assured us
不出一小r我⑾但@知
that we will hear from them in some way within the hour.
居民 如你所想的那 十分震@
Residents, though, are,as you can imagine, just stunned.
我同一些不在z像C前l表言的人了
I've spoken to some people who do not want to comment on camera.
其中一位告V我...
I did speak to one, though, who told me that...
- 可z的煞 - 悲 真正的悲
Poor Zev.        Tragic. Absolutely tragic.
他一定不知道他在做什N
He couldn't have known what he was doing.
他很清楚他在做什N
He knew exactly what he was doing.
什N 你是什N意思 R克斯
What? What are you talking about, Max?
他⒌舻哪人
The man he killed
叫做炷岵特・斯德姆
was named Kunibert Sturm.
而煞虻恼婷
And Zev's name
叫做W托・瓦利施
was Otto Wallisch.
就是他...
They were the men who...
⒑α宋业募胰
murdered my family.